Hi, I'm Robert Nizza, with the BTI group, in San Francisco.
I'd like to speak with you, about how to sell part of your business.
Before you start thinking about selling part, ask yourself, what are my goals, my objectives for wanting to sell part of the business?
What will I be getting for that?
Most small businesses are sold as a complete asset sale.
We don't usually sell just part of the business, but let's say you did.
One of the things that the buyer would want to see, is what is the value of this part of your business?
So if you do have a separate division of your business, or a product line that you do want to sell, it's really crucial to represent that accurately, in terms, of how much revenue does that product generate, and what the expenses are associated with that product, or different division of the company, so that you can fully represent, what exactly you're trying to sell.
Basically, you want the buyer to be able to have a transparent view of what they're buying, so before you want to sell part of your business, or a product line, or something like that.
The first step is to understand why you want to sell it.
Second step, is to do some accounting, and figure out how much money, that product or service generates, what expenses are associated with it, and have that separated out, so that a buyer can accurately see, what those numbers are, so that a value can be developed from that, and those are some first steps, to thinking about how to sell part of your business.